

Immediate Joiner and seeking roles in Software Development, Project Management, Application Development, Release Management, Change Management, Requirement Gathering, Production Support, Application Support, Core Java, Hibernate, MySQL, Spring



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Current Company: Rsystems international Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Ghaziabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Gurgaon, Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Project Management, Application Development, Release Management, Change Management, Requirement Gathering, Production Support, Application Support, Core

Java, Hibernate, Eclipse, MySQL, Spring, Putty, Microservices, java 8

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

5 years of total working experience in Software development

Proficiency in Core Java ,Java 8 ,Spring Boot and Microservices, Rest Web Services with Windows and Linux Platform.

Hands on experience of J2EE, Spring and Hibernate Framework.

Have good experience in interaction with the clients.

Excellent end user interaction in understanding the issues, analyzing and resolving the same.

Implemented various urgent change requests during the application support phase fulfilling all the requirements.

Prepared, executed and documented the unit, system and regression test cases for the application undertaken.

Highly motivated and energetic with good analytical, organizational and communication skills and keen to learn new Technologies.

Ability to work independently as well as in a team.

Work Experience

Rsystems international as Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2020 to Till Date

Working as Senior Software Engineer responsible for below duties /tasks.

- 1)Researching, designing, implementing and managing software programs.
- 2)Identifying areas for modification in existing programs and subsequently developing these modifications
- 3)Writing and implementing efficient code.
- 4) Maintaining and upgrading existing systems.
- 5) Working closely with other developers, UX designers, business and systems analysts
- 6)Peer Code reviews.
- 7) Helping the QA team in Functional Testing, Reviewing BDD's.

Amdocs as Software Developer

Sep 2019 to Feb 2020

4 years of total working experience in Software development

Proficiency in Core Java, Rest Web Services with Windows and Linux Platform.

Hands on experience of J2EE, Spring and Hibernate Framework.

Have good experience in interaction with the clients.

Excellent end user interaction in understanding the issues, analyzing and resolving the same.

Implemented various urgent change requests during the application support phase fulfilling all the requirements.

Prepared, executed and documented the unit, system and regression test cases for the application undertaken.

Highly motivated and energetic with good analytical, organizational and communication skills and keen to learn new Technologies.

Ability to work independently as well as in a team.

Fidelity Investment as Analyst Programmer

Mar 2019 to Jul 2019

Role

ANALYST PROGRAMMER Team Size:

15 Description:

Project Overview: Customer Enquiry Service is the pass web service which provides customer related services to end users. It provides a REST (Representational State Transfer) based interface (API's) to web while accessing customer Enquiry Service.

Platform: Windows, Linux Programming Language: Java Framework: Spring-Boot

Tool: Bamboo, Teamcity, UDeploy, Bitbuckit Responsibilities:

- 1. Responsible for development and implementation of small to medium non-complex components of a project module.
- 2. Fixing Bugs in Dev and Production Environment and did Ubuntu upgrade changes in Customer Enquiry.
- 3. Creating & Executing JUnit Test cases for different functionalities.
- 4. Worked in the environment of agile process and implementing the user stories.

Agnity Communications as Member Technical Staff

Jul 2015 to Jan 2019

Description:

Project Overview: OSG is the Web Services Gateway to OVM platform. The communication between OSG & OSG Clients uses HTTP protocol. OSG accepts XML requests (wherever large amount of data need to be posted in request) along with some URL parameters and after processing sends response in XML format (wherever data need to be returned in response) along with HTTP response code. The OSG provides a REST (Representational State Transfer) based interface (API's) to DVC for interacting with the OVM.

Platform: Windows, Linux Programming Language: Java Framework: Restlet2.0x Tool: Ant, Bitbuckit

IDE: Eclipse Responsibilities:

- 1. Requirement gathering and analysis by interaction with client.
- 2. Design and development of Rest API using Restlet framework.
- 3. Deploying application on Server.
- 4. Creating Dev environment on local and remote servers.
- 5. Performed the unit and system testing.
- 6. Identify risks and raise it for better quality.
- 7. Work towards deadlines and prioritizing workload.
- 8. Provided hot fixes in urgent code change request raised by client.
- 9. Mentored the trainees during development and bug fixing.
- 10. Prepared the proper document and release notes for various releases.

Description:

Project Overview: SBM have requested to enhance the Email Mx product for 3-Node Cassandra stall case. When Cassandra nodes fall in this state, Email-Mx MSS can't access one of the token range of the Cassandra nodes. SBM required that Email- Mx should mitigate such scenario. When multiple Cassandra nodes get stalled in a way that MSS can't access one of the token range of the Cassandra nodes, then we need to provide Temporary Mailbox Access Capability using the Referral MSS Cluster (fixed for a Primary MSS Cluster). As per the requirement value of mssClusterFailoverState Idap attribute is required by IMAP server and MTA to determine if referral is true or not.

Platform: Windows, Linux Programming Language: Java

Framework: Spring Tool: Maven, Bitbuckit

IDE: Eclipse Responsibilities:

- 1. Design and development of Rest API's using Jersey on Spring Framework.
- 2. Deploying the changes on local and production Server.
- 3. Unit testing and Regression Testing
- 4. Fixes the bug in production

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from ABES ENGINEERING COLLEGE GHAZIABAD in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used Experience	
core Java,jdbc	3		2 Year(s) 2 Month(s)
Multi-,Threading,Rest Web Services	JDK 7		2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Spring3.0, Hibernate,Restlet,Struts2.0x	4		2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
ECLIPSE, MyEclipse	Kepler,Lun	0	3 Year(s) 2 Month(s)
Apache's Ant, Maven, Win SCP			
Windows XP/Vista/7/8/8.1,			
Linux (CentOs, Ubuntu)			
MySQL, Oracle Cassandra			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Hindi	Expert			
English	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: SCAP Self Care and Administration Portal

Client: AT&T

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2017 - Mar 2018 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: The SCAP provides a WEB based Graphical User interface (GUI) for provisioning Email Gateway services by

subscribers. A subscriber can perform various operations using WEB User-Interface.

Project Title: OSG(Open Service Gateway 6.0)

Client: Comcast

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2017 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Project Overview: OSG is the webservices interface to OVM plateform.OSG accepts XML requests along with some URL parameters and after processing sends response in XML. The communication between OSG & OSG Clients using HTTP protocol.

Project Title: Mailbox Accees Capablity

Client: Openwave Systems Nature of Employment: Full Time

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Details: SBM have requested to enhance the Email Mx product for 3-Node Cassandra stall case. Recently Cassandra nodes in SBM stalled because of compaction of large stable which stacked undeleted tombstone data of repair process with deep merle trees.

Duration: Aug 2016 - Apr 2017

When Cassandra nodes fall in this state, Email-Mx MSS can't access one of the token range of the Cassandra nodes. SBM required that Email-Mx should mitigate such scenario.

Project Title: WeMo Cloud Client: Belkin India Pvt. Ltd.

https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=4a37fbe49b3852003313de48df95dbd90c0e09021c120112051915585f... 1/22/2021

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jul 2015 - Dec 2015 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Project Overview: WeMo is a growing family of innovative, easy-to-use products that use mobile internet to control your home electronics, power, water, and Wi-Fi right from your smartphone or tablet. WeMo also works withIFTTT, connecting your home electronics to a whole world of online apps

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time